Tanay Telsinge

Katraj, Pune +91 8796644401 / 8208523051 tanaytelsinge@gmail.com

PROFILE

Almost 3 years experience in full stack web development.

I have worked on Monolith as well as microservice architecture with tasks such as UI Redesign, handling backend of mobile app independently, implementing OAuth 2.0 authentication and debugging to resolve priority client issues and bug fixes as part of Agile Scrum Team.

EXPERIENCE

Autodesk, India.

May 2022 - Sept 2022

Handling Fusion 360 mobile app backend independently. Work profile involves handling security issues, creating tasks based on discussion from Manager and planning it in sprint, maintenance of existing product.

Implemented and deployed OAuth 2.0 based login flow for Autodesk Fusion 360 mobile app having approx 15000 users.

Maxxton Technologies

Dec 2021-May 2022

Hospitality management product with microservice architecture.

Delivered various enhancements and bug fixes in backend side.

Zebra Technologies, Pune — *Software Engineer*

SEP 2019 - DEC 2021

Redesigned the UI of my module in the company's web based application with WCAG and ADA compliance standards.

Wrote modular, secure and well tested code for web services and web apps in AngularJS/Spring.

Worked in Agile Software Development Team to complete various stories through sprints.

Investigated errors to reproduce issues and develop software fixes.

SKILLS

ReactJS Javascript
Spring Java Git
MySQL Microservices

LANGUAGES

English, Hindi, Marathi.

EDUCATION

CDAC - Sunbeam Institute, Pune — *PG Diploma in Advance Computing*

August 2019 - Percentile: 65.20%

TKIET, Warnanagar — B.E. Mechanical

June 2016 - Percentile: 68.35%

Sharad Institute of Technology, Polytechnic, Ichalkaranji — Diploma in Mechanical Engineering

April 2013 - Percentile: 75.00%

PROJECTS

Antique Ecommerce Website (as part of CDAC) — *Angular 6, Hibernate, Spring*

Developed a website for selling antique goods online. UI developed in Angular 6 communicated with microservices developed in Spring connected to DB through Hibernate.

Sellers can add, update or remove a product according to specific category. The buyer can log in to the website and buy the goods. 5% charges will be levied on the product price which will be the earning of the website.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- -Implemented and deployed OAuth 2.0 based login flow for Autodesk Fusion 360 mobile app having approx 15000 users.
- -Member of Best Outgoing Team in CDAC Aug 2019.
- -was recognized for contribution and commitment by Manager as well as Director, Software Engineering of my current organization in development June 2021.